Near 1299
Episode 90
Sons.
This is İnegöl Castle.
Look at it carefully.
Carefully.
We'll march there first.
Then...
we have Bursa, protected
by Keşiş Mountains.
then, Constantinople...
and then, the whole world.
I took this cause from my father...
and you will leave it to your children.
And they will leave it to their
children.
We'll become a state.
We'll have endless campaigns.
We'll have endless battles.
My children.
We were born on horseback...
we'll die on horseback.
A horse is our purpose.
A horse is the wings of Turks.
And when we mount a horse...
we always go forward!
We always crave a campaign...
we always want conquest.
What takes us forward are two wings.
Orhan, tell me.
What is one of those wings?
Cause of the world's order.
To bring Allah's order to the
whole world.
Alahaddin.
Tell me the other wing.
Allah's words, father.
Indeed.
That's why we swing our swords.
That's why we ride
our horses.
And our cause is the cause
of Allah.
Until the whole world is
ruled justly...
until the oppressed have no
more to worry about...
we'll be on the neck of the tyrants!
My children!
Come on!
Let's gallop for our dreams!
-Come on!
Where will the passage
take us, father.
There is an exit in every trouble.
What's important is knowing
the way.
If you know the way,
worry not.
But if you don't, you should
take caution.
Boran!
My bey!
Come.
Go.
Alright, my bey.
Come on.
My children.
What is this place, father?
The beginning of the road
to the conquest, Orhan.
It's the den of the alps who
burn with the desire of jihad.
All power to your elbow!
Thank you, my bey.
Thank you.
Welcome, my bey.
Salam Alaikum.
-Alaikum Salam.
-All power to your elbow.
Welcome, my bey.
Thank you, Master Davud.
Welcome, my shehzads.
Tell me about the situation.
Come, my bey.
I've done all the calculations, my bey.
The catapults will be
located like this.
They will hit the walls...
and these will destroy the gate,
inshallah.
What about...
the range of these catapults?
They will be enough, my bey.
If the wind blows the
opposite way...
would they hit us instead?
I knew that you would ask this, my bey.
I strengthened the balls against
the wind.
Allah's angels helped the warriors
of Bedr. If they help us too...
no wind can stop us.
Inshallah.
If we have the faith of the lions
of Bedr...
the army of the angels will stand with us.
Right, Mullah Alahaddin?
True words, my bey.
Mashallah.
Mashallah to my valiant.
My bey.
Children.
Tell me, Konur.
My bey.
As you ordered, Cerkutay has been
gathering intelligence.
He is in İnegöl now.
A troop is gathering weapons and
Rum Fire from Constantinople...
to İnegöl.
They are almost there.
But Cerkutay says that...
if we don't stop the caravan...
it will create great trouble for us.
Weasel Nikola.
Then, we'll strike at once.
Wouldn't attacking a caravan break
the peace, my bey?
That caravan has weapons, my shehzad.
If they declare war on us
for attacking the caravan...
he'll be guilty for gathering
ammunition in his castle.
Nikola won't even see what's coming.
We'll strike him like lightning.
He won't even be able to chase it.
We want to come too, my bey.
You have the right.
Of course.
But you aren't capable enough to
go to war yet.
Prove yourself during hunting...
then, I'll say that you are ready.
Alright, my bey.
Then, we need to hunt.
Don't.
Don't return empty handed.
As you order, my bey.
Baysungur.
My bey.
Come on.
What about the gathering in Söğüt?
Good. We won't go there empty-handed.
But I'll go and position
early for the ambush.
Don't be late.
My bey.
One of us should be with you.
Allow me to ride alone.
İnegöl Castle
It looks like a valuable
fabric, Simon.
It's very precious, sir.
It's Chinese silk.
It's a very old fabric,
left from Sasamis.
They are using it to cover
the saints.
Am I a saint, Simon?
It's for the funerals of the saints.
But you are standing next to me
like an ancient statue.
You deserve it more than them.
When will it come?
It's on the way, sir.
We have a peace treaty with
Osman.
No one should know about
that ammunition.
Do you get it?
I calculated everything.
Don't worry, sir.
Be like shadows, Simon. No one will
hear about you.
Soon, lords will come. Even they should
not know who you are.
Now...
take your saint fabrics and leave.
My regards.
Don't idle around, Simon.
Salam Alaikum, valiants.
Alaikum Salam, Gencebay.
Gencebay!
-How are you, brother?
-I'm good, Boran. You?
Thank Allah.
Mashallah!
-How are you, Master Davud?
-Thank Allah, my valiant.
-You too?
-I'm good.
Alaikum Salam.
You haven't been around.
Where were you?
We fought the heathens in Şuşa
and Karabağ.
Thank Allah.
Who is this valiant?
A Caucasian Turk.
I'm Şamil.
I heard that Osman Bey is raising
a banner of jihad.
I wanted to be a part of it.
Welcome.
You are a fortunate man, brother Şamil.
We are going on a campaign
just as you came.
Thank Allah.
Good.
There shouldn't be a problem, ladies.
Be careful.
They are the personal order of
the lord of Bilecik.
Mashallah. It's shining.
Even my eyes can see the beauty of it.
Well done, ladies.
It's beautiful.
Good day, ladies.
Thank you, Bala Hatun.
Aygül.
They are the best products.
It's all completed.
Mashallah.
Look at my mother.
She is still working.
She never rests.
She begins as the sun shines.
-May Allah give her strength.
-Amin.
Amin. Amin.
It shouldn't be talked about but
her pain is growing.
She keeps going to the healer
for her back.
Oh, my beautiful mother!
Bala!
-What would we do without you?
-Bala, my pretty girl.
What did you do?
What did my children do?
They went with their father
to drill.
Good old days.
Ertuğrul Ghazi would take Osman
with him to drill.
He would teach him how to
fight, how to ambush.
I have limited breaths to take
in this world.
Some advice from your mother.
Raise your sons like warriors...
and your angelic daughters
as a hatun.
The greatest legacy of a parent
is raising a good child.
Look.
Osman expanded Ertuğrul Ghazi's
home.
Now, Orhan and Alahaddin will
expand it even more.
Inshallah.
Mongols, Crusaders...
These wars tired us out.
It's enough suffering for the Muslims.
Now, you have the greatest mission
for better tomorrows.
Raise good children.
Go to your jobs now.
My Allah.
Grow the fire of jihad
in my heart.
My Allah.
You...
grow the fire of jihad
in my heart.
My Allah!
Destine me with victories!
Destine me with conquests!
Amin, my Allah!
Amin.
My bey.
I'm coming from İnegöl's marketplace.
Simon is bringing the goods.
They'll come behind the green hillside.
Good.
Let them come.
My bey.
It's good that they come.
But...
where are our alps?
No.
My bey...
will we ambush the whole
caravan on our own?
What is it, Cerkutay?
Are you afraid?
I came here, trusting you.
My bey. Thank you.
Let's die if you say so.
Let's die, but...
Where is my old Cerkutay?
Years made you too old.
Where is that brave Cerkutay?
-Where is that crazy Cerkutay?
-My bey!
I'll strike them all on my own, my bey.
You trusted me.
I'll turn the world into hell
for them.
This is it!
Mashallah to my Cerkutay.
Go now.
As you order, my bey.
Godspeed.
Thank you, my bey.
Thank you.
Alps!
Welcome.
Thank you, my bey.
He is just as I heard about his renown.
Look at this valiant!
Alps!
For the love of
the three, the seven, and the forty!
-Are you ready for jihad?
-We are!
Are you ready for jihad?
-What is jihad for?
-For Allah's approval!
-Are you ready to be a ghazi?
-We are!
-Are you ready to be a martyr?
Allahu Akbar!
Allah is immortal!
Allah is righteous!
To be honest, I never
wanted peace.
But we are profiting from it the most.
We are trading with Osman.
He'll bring me a lot of goods soon.
I'm sure that he is mad that he is
trading with us and not fighting.
I don't even want to hear Osman's name.
Aren't you old friends?
Old friends can be enemies too, Vasilius.
Nikola is a close witness.
We fought a lot with Osman.
But still, you feel better with
people of the same blood...
same faith, same language.
Dear Vasilius.
Kosses returned from his mistake
even though it was late.
Anyway, let's put these matters
aside.
Justinianus and I have great
news for you.
Brother.
Orhan! Alahaddin!
Don't go far!
Baysungur Alp!
We let it run away.
Dear lords...
We grow our friendship with Basilleus.
I'm marrying his stepdaughter Holofira.
You are all invited to the wedding.
I congratulate you.
Your ties are stronger now.
These lands need this.
For peace.
Peace. Peace is very important.
Yes.
As you know, others also live
in these lands.
So, we need to grow peace
and stability with them too.
I think he is talking about Turks.
We've been living in peace
with Turks for long years.
True.
This wedding will strengthen our ties.
And for this reason, Turks, Osman Bey,
Turgut Bey...
Barkın Bey, and all big Turkish beys
will be invited.
They should come. So that the peace
can last forever.
Good.
Very good idea.
So, why didn't you inform me
sooner?
Or maybe you should've informed
me when you are informing the Turks.
It seems like I'm as far away from
you as them.
Michael Kosses.
Please don't think that.
It all happened suddenly.
Otherwise, you would hear it first.
Justinianus.
You know it, I love you
as if you are my own nephew.
But I'm still mad.
Because all preperations have to
be done in a hurry.
I can't let people say that
great Micahel Kosses...
came to Justinianus'
wedding empty-handed!
Pardon me, lords.
I'm in a hurry.
Come on.
My dear friends, this will be a wedding
to remember.
It'll be amazing.
Osman's head will be a great present.
Not only Osman.
I hope that he'll come
with his family.
My stepdaughter and Justinianus,
lord of Bilecik are getting married.
Osman and his family's death will
be the greatest present to this marriage.
Not only Osman.
Gündüz, Turgut, their wives,
their children!
Everyone! All of them will die!
Only one person will left standing.
And that's Barkın.
Barkın?
You trust Barkın.
I understand that.
Do you trust Kosses?
Kosses is a very old friend of mine.
And I know him enough to
not trust him, Basilleus.
What will we do?
Kosses haven't talked to Osman
all these times.
But still, he has something in him
for Osman... He likes him.
We must consider this.
So...
to end the war before it starts,
a little price...
Just before the wedding, Kosses
will die.
Caravan leader, this is the
end of the road.
No, it ends in İnegöl.
You say so?
We have a peace treaty.
This road belongs to all of us.
But if you value your lives,
get out of our way.
Your goods and lives
are at our mercy now.
I don't waste my time speaking in a
situation that I can solve with my sword.
Soldiers!
It's been a long time since
we spilled Turkish blood.
Attack!
Come here!
Wait here.
Simon.
Come here.
Where are you running to
without the ammunition?
So, you are bringing weapons
to kill Turks?
Your intention is to
break the peace, huh?
But the only place you can run
to...
is my wrath.
Kill me.
No. No.
You will live.
And you'll tell Nikola that I attacked
the caravan.
If he considers it as breaking
the peace...
tell him that...
I'll use these weapons
as evidence.
He should face me if he
has the heart.
Come on.
Mother.
Food is handed out to the people
in the tribe and in Söğüt.
Everyone is fed.
Well done, my pretty girl.
There isn't anyone hungry.
Thank Allah.
No one will be left hungry
under Osman Bey's rule.
Inshallah.
What did our mighty prophet
Muhammed said?
''The one who sleep full when their
neighbor is hungry, isn't one of us.''
May Allah destine us to be
one of them.
Amin.
Livelihood turns plenty
when shared.
May it be plentiful.
Inshallah.
Seeing you like this pleases me.
I know...
our tribe is protected by
the valiant ladies of Kayı.
Mother. Look here.
Come.
Is it as you wanted?
Mashallah, my pretty girl.
It's very good.
Well done.
Thank you, mother.
With the name of Allah.
This isn't our hand. It's the
hand of our Mother Fatma.
May it be plentiful.
Amin.
Here, my girl.
May Allah bless your hands
and mouth, mother.
We are almost ready for iftar.
With the name of Allah.
Söğüt is also provided with meals.
söğüt is also provided with meals, mother.
They will all eat it at iftar.
Thank you, my pretty girl.
Leave me alone!
My God, protect me!
Ya Allah!
We won't hurt you.
We want to help.
There is no time.
Let's go.
Where did they come from?
Here.
Get in there.
Damn it!
We can't go before finding her.
Hurry! Spread out!
Come on.
Here.
Söğüt
Behold! Osman Bey!
-Salam Alaikum.
-Alaikum Salam.
Go on.
With mighty Allah's ninety-nine names,
who fills our hearts with faith.
With the name of Allah.
Years have passed.
We haven't fought for a long time.
But we weren't idle either.
We expanded our tribe.
We strengthened Söğüt.
And our alps grew stronger.
Our swords sharpened.
We aren't the only ones who
did that, Osman Bey.
So did the lords.
They are stronger.
I heard that Nikola is positioning
soldiers in villages.
One caravan comes after another.
And he is inviting swords-for-sale
to his castle.
The war is near, my bey.
It shouldn't be far.
They aren't scary.
Now, tell me.
Aren't you stronger?
Didn't your trade increase
after the peace?
If not...
look at Barkın Bey.
His treasury surpassed us all.
Look at him and take an example.
Mashallah, Barkın Bey.
Mashallah.
Not at all, Turgut Bey.
Our belongings and existence is
for the future of the Turks.
Thank you.
Where are you going to?
Look at these.
A few Turkmen children.
Leave us alone!
I will.
But this lady is coming
with us.
All of you are chasing one
little girl!
Is this just?
She doesn't want to come!
She'll come with us!
We don't leave the ones
in need!
Over our dead bodies!
There is no time to play, brats!
Are you depending on
a single arrow?
I'll bury you in here!
Soldiers!
Come on!
You did all you could.
But I have to go with them now.
No! We can't allow it!
If you raise your hand,
you'll lose your heads!
You'll pay for this!
Alps!
Thank you, Baysungur Alp!
Mashallah, Baysungur Alp!
You are just in time.
You won't get away from me
again.
You saw what happened.
What if I wasn't here in time?
What would I say to my bey?
Tell me!
We are alright!
Thank Allah!
What's your name?
Why were you running away?
Why are you interrogating her?
Let her catch her breath.
They serve the lord of Yerhisar.
My father won't be pleased.
You know it, brother.
We are in peace.
Come on.
We'll talk the rest at the tribe.
This place isn't safe.
Alps!
Ready the horses!
Come on.
But don't forget!
Water sleeps...
but the enemy doesn't.
They'll prepare for sure.
As you ordered...
we are setting markets
everywhere.
We are expanding our trade, my bey.
But...
in the smallest inconvenience...
we don't have the power
to protect them.
The treaty stands.
We are protecting the markets
and the order with that treaty.
We'll be continuing to protect our
markets with peace, not with our swords.
Barkın Bey. Tell us, how many
alps do you have?
Don't we have enough alps to
protect our trade?
We have many valiants, my bey.
But...
drill isn't equal to experience.
We are afraid that they'll get rusty
without action.
We won't get rusty...
or die in our tents.
Your alps will always be ready.
Their drills will be difficult.
They will be made of steel.
Beys...
not only Barkın Bey...
you too, beys.
You too.
After all, the one who works
the most during peacetime...
bleeds the least during wartime.
Not only your soldiers.
You'll prepare your sisters too.
If there will be a war
as you say...
we'll be ready for it.
But...
the treaty stands for now.
We won't be the one to betray it.
O' Kayı Tribe.
When the children left,
it turned too silent.
Soon, mother.
When we send the goods to Bilecik,
we'll go after them.
-Haven't they returned yet?
-No, not yet.
We would hear it.
Have you seen them, Aygül?
They must be hunting with Osman Bey.
As I see Orhan and Alahaddin...
the fire in my heart
burns more.
The longing of my Aktemur...
it hurts my heart, mother.
Patience, my girl.
Patience.
No news?
-Isn't he returning?
-No, Bala.
I'm informed that there is
still time.
Not yet.
All those years. We haven't
even seen his face.
Your test is very difficult, sister.
May Allah give you patience.
Amin. Inshallah.
Amin.
Who is that?
Orhan and Alahaddin?
Yes, mother.
There is a girl coming with them.
Children share the fate
of their ancestors, they say.
Did Orhan already hunted
a big hunt?
Yes.
My child.
Are you alright?
I am, mother.
Son, what happened?
Are you alright?
Who is our guest?
Tell me, son.
Weren't you drilling with your father?
We did.
But then we went to hunting.
When we were hunting...
we found her getting
chased by soldiers.
We helped her.
Welcome, my girl.
Malhun.
Let our children catch their
breaths. They'll speak.
Let's get to the tent.
Bring the girl.
Come on.
Come on, son.
Welcome.
Come.
Come on.
Baysungur. Tell me what happened.
We went to the riverside to
hunt rabbits.
She was getting chased.
We attacked them.
Yarhisar Castle
Holofira...
Sir.
Holofira ran away.
We couldn't find her.
How could you let her go?
Couldn't you control
a little girl?
We caught her...
some people from the Kayı Tribe
stopped us.
We fought.
Then, they took Holofira and
ran away.
Osman.
Osman!
Go and bring Holofira to me!
My girl.
Are you alright?
Good.
Now, no one can hurt you here.
But, firstly, tell us.
Who are you?
Who is chasing you?
Don't be afraid.
This is Kayı Tribe.
You must've heard about us.
Tell us.
So that we'll know who to
protect you from.
Behold! Osman Bey!
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam, my bey.
Son.
Come.
Welcome.
Who is our daughter?
Orhan and Alahaddin found her
in the forest, my bey.
Poor girl was running away
from the lord's soldiers.
They saved the girl with
Baysungur Alp.
She didn't speak ever since
she arrived, son.
She is scared.
Tell me. What's your name?
Where are you coming from?
She was running away from
Yerhisar soldiers, father.
My name is...
Holofira.
I'm the step-daughter of the lord
of Yerhisar.
Why are you running away?
My step-father is forcing me to marry
the lord of Bilecik.
I'm not even old enough to marry.
I don't want it.
Haven't you told your step-father
that you don't want it?
Of course I did.
But he said that he can't refuse
the emperor's orders.
He is sacrificing me to get
the emperor's favor.
It's the azan.
Let's end our fasting.
We'll talk.
My sheik.
My Allah.
We are fasting for your approval...
and we are ending it with the
food you are giving.
Approve us.
Amin.
You see everything and
you hear everything.
-Accept our fasting.
-Amin.
Amin.
Come on now.
Enjoy it. With the name of Allah.
İnegöl Castle
I said that no one will enter!
My best student, Nikola!
Haven't you missed me?
Your departure...
made me really mad.
Your return...
made me happy.
After all, I don't like peace.
You were right about Kosses.
It'll be best to kill him.
So, my men and Yarhisar soldiers
set an ambush.
Kosses was always close
to Osman.
He just didn't know that
we knew it.
And I wouldn't take such a risk.
That wedding.
It'll be wedding.
And it'll bring Osman's end.
Your departure extended this
period a lot.
I left these lands to Barkın
and you.
I found you stronger than ever
when I returned.
When Osman dies...
Barkın will take over Söğüt.
Barkın?
The one who holds Söğüt...
holds the leashes
of the Turks.
Do you think the other beys
will follow Barkın?
He has been working for this
all these years.
Barkın is as valuable as Osman
for them.
Good.
Then, this will be over today.
No.
If you don't cut it from the
root, it'll sprout gain.
We'll take their roots out.
We'll take their children.
I'll kill them in Bilecik,
in front of Osman's eyes.
When it's all over...
everyone will follow Barkın.
And Barkın will obey us.
No one enters--
What happened to my ammunition?
Sir, the caravan...
It seems to me that your ammunition
is gone, Nikola.
Harmankaya Castle
Thank you for answering my invitation,
Justinianus.
It's been a long time since
we talked personally.
True.
I assume that this foziness is
because of the wedding.
It's the wedding.
You are right, Kosses.
You are just like your uncle.
Whenever I see you, I remember your
uncle Rogatus.
My old friend.
A great warrior...
and a very loyal friend.
I miss him.
I wish he could be with us
in your happy day.
I don't want you in my wedding, Kosses.
What?
Why? I thought I was
your family.
You were my uncle's friend.
You are my friend too, but...
I don't want you to come
to my wedding.
I see, Justinianus.
I won't come to your wedding.
But will you tell me why?
There is no reason, Kosses.
If you want to give me a present,
not coming will be the best present.
I see.
Osman? Will Osman come?
A trap.
They set a trap for Osman.
Thank Allah.
We are in another Ramadan.
Let's hope that Allah is pleased
with our efforts.
Amin. Amin, my sheik.
Do you know what Allah
says about this month?
When Ramadan comes...
the gates of heaven
gets opened...
the gates of hell
gets closed...
and the demons get chained.
Now, you say that...
when the demons are chained,
no sins are committed!
If it was always devil who
deceived us...
there is no one to stop in
our way...
it's time for comfort
for the Muslims!
But if you look around,
or look at yourselves...
humans commit many sins.
But, my sheik...
if Allah's prophet says that they
are chained, they are chained.
What makes us commit these sins?
It's our desires, my shehzad.
Our desires.
It's more cunning than the devil.
Our Allah chains the demons
in this month...
but we should chain
our desires too.
My sheik.
How can we chain our desires?
How can we discipline it?
I kill all the heathens...
but not my desires.
Every person's nature
and desire is different.
For example, some finds the salaat
difficult...
some finds the fasting difficult.
Some finds giving alms difficult...
the others find
the jihad scary...
and think that pilgrimage is difficult.
We should look into ourselves.
Whichever of them is the most difficult
one for us...
we'll be more busy with it.
Apart from what's a religious duty,
we'll do supererogatory prayers.
We'll give alms...
to control the stinginess
of our desires.
We'll do supererogatory prayers
to control the conceit of our desires.
After Ramadan, we'll
keep fasting...
to control the lust of our desires.
Now, tell me. What is the
greatest battle of a Muslim?
It's their battle with their desires.
Mashallah.
Then, are you ready
to fight your desires?
Thank Allah, my sheik.
Speak.
Sir, Osman...
he found our secret route.
Osman...
found our secret route?
How can Osman learn something that
only two of us knew?
How? Tell me, Simon!
How?
I don't know, sir.
Our soldiers. Weapons.
They are all gone.
I will kill him!
You can't do anything!
Anything!
You can't do anything when
you have this traitor in you!
Anything!
Tell me! Who?
Who said it?
When will the new
goods come?
The caravan is on the way.
We'll receive them tonight.
Tonight?
That Turkish merchant.
With my helper...
Damn it!
That idiot must've spoken!
Good.
Then, you know who to kill
before Osman, Simon!
Will we attack, sir?
Simon... Simon...
Why do you think I gather
all these ammunation for?
Why?
For nothing?
We won't act openly!
We won't!
Do you understand it, Simon?
-Yes.
-Out, Simon. Out.
Idiots!
May I enter, my bey?
Come.
My bey, Yerhisar's lord
sent someone.
Let him come.
Yerhisar's lord Basilius sent
his regards.
Lord Bailius wants his daughter Holofira.
Please, don't give me.
Please, don't give me!
Please!
As you see, Holofira is our guest.
And she has spoken.
She doesn't want to come with you.
But, Osman Bey, Lord Basilius--
Get out of my sight!
I'm grateful.
Emperors never meddle with the
marriages of the lords.
Holofira.
Tell me all about it from
the beginning.
You brought prosperity
to the bey's table.
Thank you.
Today, Osman Bey asked a question
at the council.
He asked if we have the might
to protect all our markets.
Now, I ask you.
-Tell me.
-Barkın Bey.
Our tribe is in prosperity,
just like your table.
So is the numbers of our alps.
Ergün Bey is right.
Numbers of our alps have surpassed
many other tribes.
We have the might to protect all the
markets including Söğüt.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-Thank Allah.
You made me happy.
Thank you.
But tell me...
who has the future
of the Turks?
Whoever feeds us has
our loyalty.
Barkın Bey has
the future of the Turks.
Barkın Bey.
We follow Barkın Bey.
We are loyal to Barkın Bey.
May I enter, my bey.
Come.
Gencebay.
What did you do in your homeland?
Tell us.
We ran after the tyrants as if
we were running after dogs!
They didn't expect it.
We fought fiercely.
We didn't leave them space.
We avanged the innocent.
The tyrants learned it well, brothers.
If you hurt the innocent,
this is what you get.
Play your kopuz, brother.
Feed our souls.
Trouble always finds us.
Some people prove to be brave.
Hundreds of Moses become a wall
against the modern Pharoahs.
Ibrahims fight against the
Nimrods of this century.
Every side of the world,
in the dungeons of the tyrants...
thousands of alps are ready
for independence.
Turk means hope.
Laws orders,
when that holy day comes...
the game ends when the Turks
come to the battlefield.
The treacherous order gets
destroyed when the Turks come.
Even if they always set ambushes,
the enemy can't get to us.
Turks love their creator, and they are
the nightmare of the tyrants.
Turks march on the righteous path,
as all traps get destroyed.
Almighty Allah, ensure us,
strengthen our army.
Take the world, give it to the Turks.
Let Turan become a state.
Make our state fair and just,
make it the head of the world.
They founded many states,
armies of wolf banners.
The enemies of the Turks get
questioned by Almighty Allah.
The enemies of the Islam get
They founded many states,
armies of wolf banners.
The enemies of the Turks get
questioned by Almighty Allah.
Almighty Allah questions the enemy
of Islam.
-Praise be!
Can we come in, Osman Bey?
Come in, brother!
We have no time.
I wouldn't have come at midnight if it
wasn't so important.
What is it?
You are invited to the Yarhisar Lord and
Bilecik Lord's wedding tomorrow.
Don't go.
It is a trap. They are going to kill you.
Devil!
I have helped him all this time.
I saved his life many times.
But...
...no loyalty...
...none.
The devil has his army but...
...we have our mighty friendship.
Thank you, Kosses.
I won't forget this favor of yours.
Thank you.
So, what will you do?
You left untimely, you come untimely.
However, I slept.
I have just waited.
But no matter what you still came.
I keep my promise, Barkın.
Was it worth leaving, Sir?
I saved Jerusalem.
Now it is time to save Rome.
How are there?
Argun is dead. Geyhatu is in control now.
He is resting in delight.
He has no intention to fight.
If you are asking these lands...
...you will help me.
I can't be İbrahim Faki anymore.
I've built this trust so hard.
Just to break Osman.
Tell me, what will I do?
First, you will tell me about the tribe.
What happened to whom?
What did the last years do to Kayı?
What did it do?
It strengthened it.
Where does the iron from Nikola's mine go?
I've been wondering this for years
as well.
But I couldn't find out.
Did the light dazzle you, Barkın?
It made you blind.
Remember that those in the dark always
see.
What will be our move?
Our move will be to solve this problem
radically.
Osman will be murdered at
the wedding in Bilecik.
Why are you interested in mines if Osman
is going to die?
For you, Barkın. For you.
For your state.
What will I do?
Osman will die. His children will die.
Kosses will die.
You will take Söğüt.
And will be the sole ruler of the Turks.
The wedding is built for us.
What are you saying, my Bey?
Is it a trap?
They will try to kill us at the wedding.
But...
...they are using Holofira to lure us
to the trap.
Those dogs!
They waited all these years and decided
to attack now?
What kind of a father would involve his
child in this dirty game?
They couldn't beat us openly.
They kept getting close all these years.
Just to get to our backs, Osman Bey!
Good, my Bey.
You say knowledge is everything.
Then, we won't give Holofira.
We won't send the goods as well.
Then, we will organize an expedition
to Bilecik at the first opportunity.
No.
Actually, now we will give Holofira to his
father.
She will go to the wedding.
We will drink the sherbet of martyrdom
instead of the poisoned sherbet.
We will both give them the wedding
gifts...
...and take the castle.
And take the Holofira too and return.
The war is at our door, Selvi.
Osman is terribly cornered.
His and...
...those with him are near to their end.
What is in your mind?
What should we do, Barkın?
We will think about ourselves.
We will protect your fathers' legacy.
Our heads will always stay up.
We won't fight for Osman but for
ourselves.
If necessary, we will be against Osman.
What are you saying, Barkın?
Osman Bey has always been so good to us.
If we've been living here in peace
all this time...
...Osman Bey's share in this is quite big.
Osman Bey's only wish was to make us
thankful to him, my Selvi.
We took what was ours.
He thinks he granted it.
I want to live in peace, Barkın.
I don't want to get separated.
Oh, my beautiful Hatun.
Osman never saw us as one of his own.
He rose above by stepping on us.
It is enough. It is our turn to rise.
Let's talk about this later.
There is a wedding, we shouldn't be late.
Come on.
No, Selvi!
I don't let you to the wedding.
I am leaving now.
You think thoroughly about what we talked.
Think until you share the same decision
as me, Selvi.
This is dangerous.
How many people are involved...
...how many soldiers are waiting for us...
...the other Lords invited...
We finalized our decision, Konur.
If we know the trap...
...they will be the ones to get trapped.
Right! We will go with the alps and
destroy the castle and those dogs!
No.
If we go with the alps...
...they will see that we are aware of
the trap.
You will go.
We will conquer the castle with Kayı's
Hatuns.
And Bilecik Castle will be ours.
We will share the spoils we took
from there...
...with our army.
We will encourage our army.
We will dress them with swords.
We will walk to İnegol with
the preparations we have made...
... all this time.
The women have been waiting for this day.
They have been waiting to fight.
Thankfully, it is time!
No move, no wall, no trap...
...can't stand before us anymore!
It is time for war. Time to conquer!
Protect me, God!
I thought we were friends, Osman Bey.
What made you think otherwise, Basileus?
Tell me.
What you did yesterday.
You retained my daughter.
You were supposed to send her to me.
Basileus...
...if I had delivered your daughter to
someone else and not you...
...our friendship would be damaged.
In that case...
...I hope you will honor our friendship.
I will take Holofira and leave.
Sure.
Sure, I will deliver you what
you entrusted to me.
-Boran!
-My Bey.
Bring Holofira.
As you order, my Bey.
Don't be afraid.
You will make me very happy if you come
to my daughter's wedding...
...with your whole family, Osman Bey.
Please don't reject my intivation.
Thank you.
Since you invite us to the wedding...
...of course, we will accept
the invitation.
The dog showed its face, Boran.
It is time to be a wolf against that dog.
We will destroy their traps upon them!
As you order, my Bey.
As Osman falls into the trap of the Lords
...
...we will achieve our goal.
Find me such men that...
...they hold the dead in their palms.
As you order, my Bey.
I won't wait anymore. Söğüt will be mine.
Now go.
I will find out where the iron coming from
the mines go.
Praise be!
The best of blacksmith apprentices!
Do you know why I called you here?
You will make me a sword.
But only you.
Now, listen to me.
I wish I could come as well so that you
wouldn't be alone.
But one of us has to stay at the tribe
for our children, Malhun.
We worry about our children but...
...that so-called Lord doesn't show mercy
to that little girl!
We know her father but what about her
mother?
Is she alive?
What kind of a mother would get her child
in such a dirty game?
We don't know that much.
The girl wanted to go to Bursa, to her
aunt.
How good you said, Bala Hatun.
Her only wish was to go to her aunt
safe and sound.
My Orhan...
...but the conditions prevented it.
You know your father did the best he
could.
I promised her that my father wouldn't
let her down.
How about that, mother Bala?
My soft-hearted child!
My Orhan...
...your father made the best decision.
Besides, maybe there is something he
knows.
It is not our place to criticize it.
Brother Orhan.
Brother Orhan! My Sheik Grandfather
is waiting.
We have a drill in the lodge. We are late!
Orhan! Alaaddin!
Take your swords. We are going to
the lodge.
Come on.
This is inside of Bilecik.
We get this map redrawn every time we go.
Since they are setting a trap for us...
...we are taking measures.
When we are at the saloon with Turgut Bey
...
...you will disperse around.
-Boran.
-My Bey.
Konur.
You will keep close to the Lords'
Commanders.
You will kill them without an order
at their first move.
As you order, my Bey.
Be careful.
These cowards do not always attack
with a sword.
They won't hesitate to use poison.
Right.
Kamil, did you bring the antidote Kumral
Abdal gave you?
I did, my Bey.
Thank you.
Praise be that you considered every
measure.
-Of course!
-Thank you.
-Gence Bey.
-Yes, my Bey.
Turhan.
The secret passage left from Rogatus
still works.
You will bring the rest of the alps
through there.
As you order, my Bey.
Sisters will go inside with the goods.
And we will go inside via the wedding.
Praise be!
Praise be, to my valiants!
Come on.
Take the ones my Sheik finished to
the oven.
Allaaddin, pour some water to
my hands, son.
Come on.
Enough, enough. Thank you
You are tired, grandfather.
You sweat blood.
Wouldn't it be better to leave it
to the apprentices?
He that would eat the kernel must
crack the nut, son.
Would it suit me to be useless that I am
a Sheik?
I will keep working as long as
I have the strength.
Don't underestimate what we do, Shahzadas.
No way.
Do you know what makes a good Muslim?
We wish to learn, my Sheik.
All right, then.
Leave it to me, my Sheik.
Thank you, my Akça.
Sit.
A good Muslim is one with good actions.
It is to prosper the world and to be
instrumental...
... in good works that are beneficial
to humans, nature and animals.
My job is to make jugs.
To make pottery.
If good food is cooked in women's ovens...
...happiness comes to the home.
Children who eat from that pot
have strength.
If the pot you make betrays the meal...
...it will give hard time to our sister
who cooks the meal.
What will I do if the pottery I made
embarrasses her...
...to her husband? Right, my Shahzadas?
With this love, I make these pots.
With that spirit, I still work at this
age.
A Muslim can't lay around.
He must always be on duty.
Don't forget, sons...
...as a man's work is...
...so is his faith.
The work of a man who does not do
his job well and cheats...
...never goes well.
His faith is also tied by a thread.
You should be smart and never cheat.
What did I tell you just before?
A Muslim can't lay around, my Sheik.
He must always be on duty.
-Come on, brother.
Come on. Praise be!
Come on, valiants!
Praise be to you, my boys!
Alps!
Brothers!
Years of peace are now coming to an end!
But this end is a new beginning!
Not it is the time of conquest!
Bilecik Castle will be...
...the property of the Turks before
the sun rises again!
Allahu Akbar! Allahu Akbar! Allahu Akbar!
Shoot!
They are as good as you said, Nikola.
Osman, Turgut, Gündüz, all of them,
all of them...
...will be shot by these snipers!
I've been laughing at Osman's face
for years.
It is frustrating, Nikola!
We will destroy all of his tribe, women
children, and his alps! All of them!
We will leave him with nothing!
Nothing at all!
Obviously, someone sent their dogs
after us.
Don't be obvious.
Let's continue as if we don't know.
Then, we will hit at the right moment.
Attack! I want the children alive!
Alps, protect the children!
Don't be afraid, brother! We will arrive
at the tribe safe and sound!
I am not afraid while you got my back,
brother!
We didn't do that much training for
nothing. It is time to show your skills!
Don't disappoint me!
-Come on! Allah!
-Allah!
Osman's weak lights!
I came to put you out!
Drop your sword! Or else, you will watch
your brother die!
-Who are you?
-I am not joking!
Drop it!
Fine! Let my brother go!
Take them!
We are going to Bilecik!
Alaaddin!
How very kind of you to come
and welcome us!
You are so kind.
Frankly, I'm not here to comrade you,
but to lead you astray.
Is that so?
Welcome.
The Christians have been fighting all
these years.
You kept being on Osman's side...
...while you are so different from him.
Osman is an honest man, Betrus.
That is enough for me.
Since you love him this much...
...you can die together!
Osman will die tonight.
We have his son, Orhan.
You are done, Kosses!
Kiros!
Back to back, Kiros!
Are you ready, Kiros?
I am, Lord Kosses!
Come on!
I am here, Kosses!
Damn it! Osman came!
Now you are doomed!
Kosses!
You hid them well, right?
They can't be seen.
Everything is done, Ayşe Hatun.
All right.
Malhun...
...you don't look well.
I haven't been able to
find Orhan since he left the tent.
He went to the lodge with Alaaddin.
He worried a great deal about the Lord's
daughter.
He was upset.
Malhun, your son is growing up.
Baysungur is with them.
They will return safe and sound.
Don't worry.
The carriages are ready to set off,
my Bala.
Sisters are ready as well.
They are waiting for your order.
Good.
Be careful.
Bless your right.
If I drink the sherbet of martyrdom...
...the children are entrusted to you.
Don't say that, Bala!
You will take Bilecik and return safely,
I hope!
I hope so.
Mother.
My beautiful daughter.
Be careful.
May your way be clear,
may your sword be sharp.
I hope so, mother.
Come on!
May Allah protect you!
Come on.
May all of you return safe and sound!
Bilecik Castle
I have been waiting for a long time,
Master Arius.
Welcome.
I didn't come empty-handed.
I brought you a wedding gift.
Nikola would be jealous.
Did you bring Turkish boys as wedding
gifts?
They are not random Turkish boys, Nikola.
They are Osman's sons.
Allaaddin.
Orhan.
Take them to the darkest part of
the dungeon.
Orhan!
Wedding preparations will continue
with all its reality.
They can never suspect anything.
Everything goes according to the plan,
Master Arius.
There is nothing to be suspected.
Osman is thinking he is coming to my
wedding.
But...
...they will come to their funeral.
Take them!
Kosses!
Hang on!
Hang on! We are taking you to Söğüt.
Osman Bey.
They took them to Bilecik!
Who?
Children.
They took the children!
Orhan...
...Alaaddin!
Who took them!
Who did? Kosses! Who did?
Kosses!
-Have you seen Orhan and Alaaddin?
-I didn't, Malhun Hatun.
My children!
My Allah, may you protect them!
Baysungur!
Baysungur! Baysungur!
Baysungur! Who did this?
Where are my sons?
They took them!
They took them, Malhun Hatun!
What are you saying, Baysungur?
Who took my sons?
They took them to Bilecik Castle!
Who?
One with a hidden face... years before...
Take Baysungur to the healing tent.
Yes, Malhun Hatun.
Come on. Come on.
Alps! Get ready!
We are going to Bilecik!
Alps!
Take Kosses to Söğüt!
Take him to my Sheik.
Come on, brothers!
Hang on, Kosses!
Hang on!
Let's enter their castle at once,
Osman Bey!
They will learn what's the price for
taking your children!
Even if my children's hair is harmed...
...I will destroy those Lords' castles
upon them!
But that is not what we will do now.
What?
-Why don't we go now, Osman Bey?
-We will.
We will go to the wedding.
We will sit on their table as if nothing
happened.
We will laugh.
We will have fun. But when the time comes
...
We will draw our swords and...
...be their wrath!
We will also take our children safely.
-Yes!
-Yes, my Bey.
Yes, my Bey.
Come on!
Brother!
Alaaddin!
My brother!
Father!
Don't come father.
Don't come.
Don't come, father.
It is a trap!
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com